<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE types [
	<!ENTITY javahl_svnkit_params SYSTEM "javahl_svnkit.txt">
]>

<ant:types 
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
	xmlns:ant="http://www.fiset.ca/ant-docs/v1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.fiset.ca/ant-docs/v1 ant-types.xsd" 
	>
	<ant:title>Svn Conditions</ant:title>
	
	<ant:introduction>
		<p>
			This document describes the conditions offered in svnant. To use those conditions,
			you must first obtain a copy of svnant.jar, add it to the classpath of your ant project
			and define the types. Fortunately, there is a resource file, within the distributed JAR file,
			and all those steps can be accomplished with the following code:
			<ant:example>
				<![CDATA[
<path id="svnant.classpath">
  <pathelement location="${svnant.dir}/lib/svnant.jar" />
  <pathelement location="${svnant.dir}/lib/svnClientAdapter.jar" />
</path>  

<typedef resource="svntypes.xml" classpathref="project.classpath"/>
				]]>
			</ant:example>
		</p>
		<p>
			If you are upgrading from an earlier version of svnant, and the following line was used
			in your <i>build.xml</i> file, then replace it with the ones above.
			<ant:example>
				<![CDATA[
<taskdef resource="svntask.properties" classpathref="svnant.classpath"/>
				]]>
			</ant:example>
		</p>
		<h3><a name="bindings">Bindings</a></h3>
		<p>
			All conditions offer two parameters: <b>javahl</b> and <b>svnkit</b>. Those parameters
			are booleans, which means their values can be set to either <b>true</b> or <b>false</b>. 
			If not specified, those parameters are assumed to be set (true). These two parameters are used
			to select which client is used to access Subversion.
		</p>
		<p>
			There are three clients used by svnant to access Subversion:
			<ul>
				<li>JavaHL;</li>
				<li>SVNKit; and,</li>
				<li>Command Line Interface.</li>
			</ul>
			To better understand the difference between those three clients, please refer to
			documentation on <b>svnClientAdapter.jar</b>.
		</p>
		<p>
			The property <b>javahl</b> is considered only if the javahl libraries are available. Similarly,
			the property <b>svnkit</b> is considered only if SVNKit is present. Finally, <b>javahl</b>
			takes precedence over <b>svnkit</b>.
		</p>
		<p>
			To better illustrate the previous paragraph, use the following steps:
			<ol>
				<li>If <b>javahl</b> is <i>true</i> and JavaHL bindings are available, then JavaHL is used.</li>
				<li>If <b>svnkit</b> is <i>true</i> and SVNKit is present, then SVNKit is used.</li>
				<li>If the two previous tests failed, for any reason, then the Command Line Interface is used.</li>
			</ol>
		</p>
	</ant:introduction>
	
	<!-- ***************************** -->
	<ant:type name="svnExists" className="org.tigris.subclipse.svnant.conditions.Exists">
		<ant:shortDescription>Ant condition that returns true if an element exists in the repository</ant:shortDescription>
		<ant:fullDescription>
			<p>
				This is a custom condition, as defined in the Ant documentation. A custom
				condition must be employed in conjunction with a <![CDATA[<Condition>]]> task
				to set a property.
			</p>
			<p>
				This custom condition is used to determine if an element exists in the repository. The condition returns
				true if the element is known to te repository. It uses a process similar to "svn info"
				to determine the existence of an element. If "svn info" can return information
				about a file or a directory, then the svnExists condition should return true for
				such file or directory.
			</p>
			<p>
				Example: determine if there exist a "build.xml" file for a project
				<ant:example>
<![CDATA[
<condition 
	property="fileExists" 
	value="true"
	else="false"
	>
	<svnExists javahl="${javahl}" svnkit="${svnkit}" target="http://svn.mycompany.com/project/trunk/build.xml"/>
</condition>
<echo>fileExists: ${fileExists}</echo>
]]>					
				</ant:example>
			</p>
		</ant:fullDescription>
		<ant:parameter name="target">
			<ant:description>
				File name or URL to the element to be queried during the condition.
			</ant:description>
			<ant:required>
				Yes
			</ant:required>
		</ant:parameter>
		&javahl_svnkit_params;
	</ant:type>
	
</ant:types>
